Guide to the Fedor Stepun Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1917-65; Series II; 8.8; (23 boxes)
  - SHORTER WRITINGS
    - "Einleitung" [to I. Turgenev]: typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1559)
    - "Erlebtes und Durchdachtes": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1560)
    - "Der Film als Ausdruck unserer Zeit":
      - Clipping from Die Zeit, 1950 Sept 7 (Box 52, Folder 1561)
      - Clipping (2 c.), Main Post, 1950 Sept 30 (Box 52, Folder 1562)
    - "Film als Kunst": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1563)
    - "Film und religiöse Gemeinschaft": typescript, carbon, corrected, initialled (Box 52, Folder 1564)
    - "F.M. Dostoevskii": typescript; and carbon, corrected, signed (Box 52, Folder 1565)
    - "F.M. Dostoevskii (k 75-letiiu so dnia ego smerti": typescript, carbon, corrected., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1566)
    - "Die Frage nach der 'Rolle Europas' in Osten"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1567)
      - Typescript, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1568)
    - "Die Funktion der Kunst in der Sowjetunion": typescript, carbon, corrected. (repaginated as part of other work) (Box 52, Folder 1569)
    - "Geburtstagsrede": typescript (2 c.), carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1570)
    - "Die gegenwärtige Lage der russischen Kirche in Sowjetrussland und in der Emigration": typescript, carbon, corrected, signed (Box 52, Folder 1571)
    - "Geist und Stil der russischer Kultur in ihrer Beziehung zum Westen": holograph and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1572)
    - "Geist und Stil der russischer Kultur in ihrer Beziehung zum Westen": review of lecture, clipping from Die Kurier, 1961 Jun 7 (Box 52, Folder 1573)
    - "Die geistigen Beziehungen zwischen Russland und Deutschland": typescript, corrected, signed, and mimeograph copy (Box 52, Folder 1574)
    - "Die geistesgeschichtlichen Grundlagen des Bolschewismus": reviews of lecture, clippings, 1960 Jul (Box 52, Folder 1575)
    - "Geistige Grundlagen des Bolschewismus": review of lecture, clipping, 1953 Jan 20 (Box 52, Folder 1576)
    - "Die geistigen Voraussetzungen der russischen Revolution": typescript, carbon. Lecture at Rhein-Kuhr club. Notation: "Original ist verbessert!" (Box 52, Folder 1577)
    - "Der geoffenbarte Gott und der herrschende Teufel in der Freiheitsphilosophie Berdjajews": typescript, carbon, corrected. On verso of letter fragment to Richard and Alice Kroner dated 1957 Nov. 4. (Box 52, Folder 1578)
    - "Germaniia o Rossii": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1579)
    - "Gestörte Begegnung mit Anna Karenina": clipping, (2 c.) from Münchner Merkur, 1954 Feb 19 (Box 52, Folder 1580)
    - "Die Glanzperiode des russischen Theaters": typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1581)
    - "Goethe und Schiller in Russland": typescript with holograph additions, lecture. With six unused notebook pages, 1963 (Box 52, Folder 1582)
    - "Goethefeirn in den Slavischen Ländern"
      - Typescript notes, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1583)
      - Typescript, carbon, holograph annotations. Part VII of lecture series "Die geistige Beziehungen zwischen Russland und Deutschland" (Box 52, Folder 1584)
    - "G.P. Fedotov"
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1585)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1586)
    - "Ein Grusswort an das Europakolleg": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 52, Folder 1587)
    - "Heimat und Fremde": review of lecture by R. Adolph, typescript, carbon (Box 52, Folder 1588)
    - "Heraus aus der heutigen Apparatur": two entire copies of Die Kultur; also includes FAS's answers to general questionnaire on pg. 11, 1959 Apr 1 (Box 52, Folder 1589)
    - "Hoffnung ist eine gute Tat": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1590)
    - "Der Höhenweg der deutschen Demokratie": typescript, corrected. verso of last page is holograph letter draft. (Box 52, Folder 1591)
    - "I.A. Bunin": typescript, corrected, [ca.1953] (Box 52, Folder 1592)
    - "I.A. Bunin i russkaia literatura": typescript, corrected, and typescript fragments (Box 52, Folder 1593)
    - "Ikone": typescript corrected, and carbon, and program of presentation (Box 52, Folder 1594)
    - "Ikonenverehrung im russischen Christentum": clipping, review of lecture, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1595)
    - "In Kreml und in kleinen Dorfkirchen": clipping (2 c.), Stimme der Heimatvertriebenen [?], 1957 Mar 24-27 (Box 52, Folder 1596)
    - "In Moskau und Petersburg"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1597)
      - Page proofs for article in Merkur [?], corrected; typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1598)
    - "Individium und Gemeinschaft: holograph, 1962 Nov 22 (Box 52, Folder 1599)
    - "Iskusstvo i sovremennost' [Stat'ia v Opytakh]:" typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1600)
    - "Iskusstvo i sovremennost'": typescript, corrected., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1601)
    - "Iskusstvo i sovremennost'[Vozdushnye puti]": typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1602)
    - "Istoriosofskoe i politicheskoe mirosozertsanie Aleksandra Bloka"
      - Holograph., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1603)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected. Lecture., n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1604)
    - "Ivan Bunin": review of article published in Letopisnye zametki (Barmherziger Samariter, 1947), clipping from Ekho, 1947 Oct 23 (Box 52, Folder 1605)
    - "Iwan Bunin": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 1606)
    - "Der Kampf des Faschismus und National- sozialismus gegen den Kommunismus": prospectus of lecture, typescript, carbon, 1935 Jan 2 (Box 53, Folder 1607)
    - "Karfreitag und Osterfest": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 53, Folder 1608)
    - "Karfreitag und Ostern": clipping from Rheinischer Merkur (3 c.), 1951 Mar 23 (Box 53, Folder 1609)
    - "Katolichestvo i pravoslavie": typescript, carbon, corrected, of interview given by FAS to Fr. Lang. Translated from German by FAS., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1610-1611)
    - "Khristianskaia tserkov' i politicheskoe sostoianie mira": holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1612)
    - "Kino i teatr": typescript, carbon, corrected, incomplete, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1613)
    - "Der konservative Mensch und die revolutionäre Situation": for radio, typescript and carbon (Box 53, Folder 1614)
    - "Kraft und Schwäche von Ost und West"
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1615)
      - Lecture, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1616)
    - "Kreise des Dostojewskij" [?]: holograph, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1617)
      Includes: TLS from J. P. Bachem Verlag (April 1964)
    - "Die Krise der Freiheit in Ost und West"
      - Typescript, carbon. Lecture, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1618)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected. Lecture, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1619)
    - "Die Krise der Freiheit in unserer und in der bolschewistischen Welt": typescript, carbon, corrected. Article (Box 53, Folder 1620)
    - "Die Krise der Freiheit in unserer Zeit": typescript, carbon, corrected, signed., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1621)
    - "Die Krisis der Freiheit": lecture, excerpt published as "Freiheit im Westen und im Osten", clipping, 1957 Mar 4 (Box 53, Folder 1622)
    - "Die Krisis der Freiheit": review of lecture, clipping, 1950 Apr 15 (Box 53, Folder 1623)
    - "Die Krisis der Freiheit in unserer Zeit": review of lecture, clipping, 1953 Oct 19 (Box 53, Folder 1624)
    - "Die Kunst des Alterns": for radio, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1625)
    - "Kunst und Kirche zur Zeit": typescript, corrected. Paginated also as part 2 of unidentified larger work (Box 53, Folder 1626)
    - "Die künsterliche und religiöse Weltschau Pasternaks": review of lecture, clipping, 1959 Mar 17 (Box 53, Folder 1627)
    - "Die künsterliche und philosophische Weltschau Pasternaks": review of lecture, clipping, 1959 Feb (Box 53, Folder 1628)
    - "Lage und Aufgabe der Kunst im Westen und der Sowjetunion": article, typescript, corrected, and carbon (Box 53, Folder 1629)
    - "Leben und Wissen": typescript, carbon, corrected. Radio speech (Box 53, Folder 1630)
    - "Lebenslauf": typescript, carbon, signed, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1631)
    - "Marina TSvetaeva": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1632)
    - "Der Mensch im technischen Zeitalter": lecture, holograph and typescript, carbon (Box 53, Folder 1633)
    - "Der Mensch im Zeitalter der Automisation": holograph and typescript pages (Box 53, Folder 1634)
    - "Miunkhen. Novaia russkaia truppa": clipping from Russkaia mysl' #1919, (4 c.), 1962 Nov 20 (Box 53, Folder 1635)
    - "Moskaus Anspruch auf das dritte Rom": typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1636)
    - "Moskaus Anspruch auf das dritte Rom": for radio, typescript, corrected, and carbon, 1964 Feb 29 (Box 53, Folder 1637)
    - "Moskva--tretii Rim"
      - Holograph. On verso are letter fragments dated 1960 April and unused notices on 75th birthday (Box 53, Folder 1638)
      - Typescript with carbon fragments, corrected., n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1639)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1640)
    - "N.A. Berdiaev": lecture, typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1641)
    - "N.A. Berdiaev": review of lecture by K. Pomerantsev, clipping from Russkaia mysl' #549, 1953 Apr 29 (Box 54, Folder 1642)
    - "Nash put'": article, typescript, carbon, corrected. Article, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1643)
    - "Nemetskii romantizm i filosofiia istorii slavianofilov"
      - Holograph draft in unidentified hand (Box 54, Folder 1644)
      - Typescript fragments, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1645)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1646)
    - "Neschwitz": typescript, carbon; "Übigauer Elegie": typescript, carbon, (2 c.), 1938 Aug 7, 1935 Aug 25 (Box 54, Folder 1647)
    - "Neskol'ko myslei po povodu mezhdunarodnogo s"ezda istorikov v Maintse"
      - Typescript, carbon, and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1648)
      - Review, clipping from Pravoslavnaia Rus' #17, 1955 Sept 14 (Box 54, Folder 1649)
    - "Nikolai Berdjajew": article, typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1650)
    - "Novogradskie razmyshleniia po povodu knigi V. S. Varshavskogo 'Nezamechennoe pokolenie' i diskussii o nei"
      - Newspaper clippings, annotated by FAS, 1956 (Box 54, Folder 1651)
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1652)
    - "Ob Antikhriste u Solov'eva": holograph (Box 54, Folder 1653)
    - "Obrashchenie k miunkhenskoi emigratsii": typescript, carbon; unidentified holograph, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1654)
    - "Das öekumenische Problem in der Geschichtsphilosophie Wladimir Solowjews": typescript, corrected, with holograph notes (Box 54, Folder 1655)
    - "Der ohnmächtige Gott und die mächte des Bösen in der Freiheitsphilosophie Nikolai Berdjajew": 2 offprints from publication in Macht und Wirklichkeit des Bösen, München- Planegg, Otto Wilhelm Barth-Verlag, 1958 (Box 54, Folder 1656)
    - "Ost und West im Kampf um den Sinn unserer Zeit": review of lecture, clipping, by A. Hoentzsch (Box 54, Folder 1657)
    - "Pamiati Evgeniia Andreevicha Gagarina": typescript, carbon, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 1658)
    - "Pamiati kniazia Sergeia Aleksandrovicha Shcherbatova": typescript, carbon (Box 54, Folder 1659)
    - "Pamiati M. A. Aldanova": holograph MS (Box 54, Folder 1660)
    - "Pamiati Sergeia Osipovicha Gessena": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1661)
    - "Pasternak": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1662)
    - "Pasternak. Zum 70 Jahr": for radio, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1663)
    - "Das Phänomen des Bolschewismus": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 54, Folder 1664)
    - "Pilger, Narr in Christo und Staretz": clipping, 1950 Dec 23/26 (Box 54, Folder 1665)
    - "Poèt - Providets. K stoletiiu so dnia rozhdeniia Vladimira Solov'eva": clipping from Za svobodu #7, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 1666)
    - "Porträt der Zeit im Zweigespräch": notice of radio address, clipping, 1960 Jan 1 (Box 54, Folder 1667)
    - "Predislovie": typescript, carbon. To unidentified book by A. Pozov, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1668)
    - "Priroda ob"ektivnosti sotsiologicheskogo poznaniia": typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1669)
    - "Das Problem des Bösen in der russischen Religionsphilosophie und Politik des 20.Jahrhunderts": typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected. Re: Marco Pallis (Box 54, Folder 1670)
    - "Proletarskaia revoliutsiia i revoliutsionnyi orden russkoi intellegentsii": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1671)
    - "Proletariat i intellegentsiia": article, holograph, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1672)
    - "Prophezeiungen von Herzen & Solowjew": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1673)
    - "Puschkin": typescript, corrected, with holograph additions; typescript, translations of poems by Pushkin, and typescript notes (Box 54, Folder 1674)
    - "Puschkin": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1962 (Box 54, Folder 1675)
    - "Pushkin i russkaya kul'tura": clipping from Za svobodu #13, 1953 (Box 54, Folder 1676)
    - "Redaktsionnyi krizis 'Sovremennykh zapisok' i sovremennoe mirovoe polozhenie": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1677)
    - "Die religionsphilosophische Lehre von Solowjew": typescript, corrected and carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1678)
    - "Der religiöse Sinn der Liebe": typescript, carbon, corrected, 1964 Jan 29 (Box 55, Folder 1679)
    - "Revnost'"
      - Holograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1680-1681)
      - Typescript, corrected, initialled; and carbon, corrected. Notation: "Kleine Arbeiten. Band 3." (Box 55, Folder 1682)
      - Typescript, carbon. German translation by H. Schult., n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1683)
    - "Die revolutionäre Intelligenz als das Subjekt der bolschewistischen Revolution": typescript, corrected, initialled, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1684)
    - "Rodina i Otechestvo": with entire issue of Za Svobodu, 1951 May 20 (Box 55, Folder 1685)
    - "Rodina, otechestvo i chuzhbina": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1686)
    - "Rossiia mezhdu Evropoi i Aziei"
      - Typescript with holograph additions, initialled, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1687)
      - Entire issue of Za svobodu #4, 1952 Aug. (Box 55, Folder 1688)
    - "Rossiia mezhdu Evropoi i zapadom: bespokoistvo Solov'eva": lecture, holograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1689)
    - "Rossiia mezhdu Vostokom i Zapadom: rech', proiznesennaia professorom F. A. Stepunom na prazdnovanii dnia russkoi kul'tury v Frankfurte 28-go iiulia, 1950-go goda": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1690)
    - "Rossiia nakanune pervoi velikoi voiny": holograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1691)
    - "Rossiia 1914-1918 g.: Kanun Voiny": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1692)
    - "Die russische Intelligenz": typescript, corrected, signed, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1693)
    - "Die russische Intelligenz und der Bolschewismus": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1694)
    - "Der russische Mensch": holograph, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1695)
    - "Die russische Literatur": holograph MS (Box 55, Folder 1696)
    - "Die russische Literatur des 20. Jahrhunderts": for radio, typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 55, Folder 1697)
    - "Russisches Ballet": typescript fragment, corrected, in re S. Lifar's Histoire du ballet russe, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1698)
    - "Die russisch-orthodoxe Kirche und die bolschewistische Revolution": for radio typescript, initialled, and carbon (Box 55, Folder 1699)
    - "Russkaia kul'tura i tekushchii moment": clipping, 1953 (Box 55, Folder 1700)
    - "Russkaia pravoslavnaia tserkov' i revoliutsiia (kratkii avtoreferat)": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1701)
    - "Russko-nemetskie otnosheniia v XIX-XX stoletiiakh": typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1702)
    - "Russland gehört zu Europa (Lebhafte Diskussion mit Fedor Stepun bei Kurt Wesemeyer)": clipping from Die Welt (2 c.), 1954 Mar 4 (Box 55, Folder 1703)
    - "Russland und Asien": holograph (Box 55, Folder 1704)
    - "Russland und Deutschland": typescript, carbon (Box 55, Folder 1705)
    - "Der Schauspieler in Theater und Film": typescript carbons (Box 56, Folder 1706)
    - "Schöner wohnen": article, typescript, carbon, corrected, of interview [with journal Schöner wohnen ?], n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1707)
    - "Sinn und Stil unserer Zeit": reviews of lecture, clippings, 1964 Jun 29 (Box 56, Folder 1708)
    - "Die Situation Russlands vor und im ersten Weltkrieg"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1709)
      - Typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1710)
    - "Solowjew - Prophet der Jahrhundertwendes": review, clipping, (2 c.), 1953 Nov 13/14 (Box 56, Folder 1711)
    - "Solowjow und das Judentum": lecture, holograph, typescript, carbon, corrected, and notes by FAS and in unidentified hand (Box 56, Folder 1712)
    - "Sovremennoe polozhenie Pravoslavnoi Tserkvi i Vestnik R. S. KH. D.":
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1713)
      - Clipping from Russkaia mysl' #1801, 1962 Feb 17 (Box 56, Folder 1714)
    - "Der sowjetische National begriff": typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1715)
    - "Die soziologische Objectivität und die christliche Existenz"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions. Article, 1957 Sept 9 (Box 56, Folder 1716)
      - Typescript, carbon, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1717)
    - "Soziologische Vorlesungen von Professor Dr. Fedor Stepun (Nach den Nachschriften von Siegfried Meinicke aus den Jahren 1927-28)": typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph additions, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1718)
    - "Das Stadtische-Schick[sal?] des Films": holograph. With cover of off-print of FAS's article "Der Film" from ed. W. Stammler, Deutsche Philologie im Aufriss, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1719)
    - "Standpunkt und Standort"
      - Article, typescript, carbon, corrected, and typescript, incomplete. On verso of pp. 1-4 are pp. 2-5 of English translation, holograph, partly in shorthand (Box 56, Folder 1720)
      - Article, typescript, carbon, corrected. Notation: "Aus dem Buch: Hier spricht München", n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1721)
      - "My Christian-Conservative View of the World", English translation by James Robert Walker: typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1722)
    - "Stanislawskij": holograph, and typescript, carbon, corrected, with holograph addition and notation "Aufsatz für die Süddeutsche Zeitung (Box 56, Folder 1723)
    - "Das Starrentum": lecture, holograph, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1724)
    - "Struktura sotsiologicheskoi ob"ektivnosti"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, and holograph fragment. On verso unused notices of 75th birthday (Box 56, Folder 1725)
      - Typescript and carbon, corrected. Notation: "Poltorazki v[on] Stepun" (Box 56, Folder 1726)
    - "Sud ili rasprava"
      - Clipping from Novoe russkoe slovo, 1960 Mar 27 (Box 56, Folder 1727)
      - Entire issue of Russkaia mysl' (4 c.), 1960 Mar 8 (Box 56, Folder 1728)
    - "Der 'Sündenfall' der russischen Seele": clipping, Lohr und Umbegung, 1952 Oct 31 (Box 56, Folder 1729)
    - "Tairoff und sein entfesseltes Theater": clipping (2 c.), 1950 Nov 24 (Box 56, Folder 1730)
    - "Theater und Film": typescript carbons, corrected (Box 56, Folder 1731)
    - "Tiazhelye dni. O sude i spravedlivosti": clipping from Armiia i Flot Svobodnoi Rossii, photostat, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1732)
    - "Tiazhelye dni. O Tverdoi pozitsii": clipping from Armiia i Flot Svobodnoi Rossii, photostat, 1917 Jul 18 (Box 56, Folder 1733)
    - "Toleranz und Christentum"
      - Typescript, corrected, 1959 Mar 8 (Box 56, Folder 1734)
      - Typescript and carbon, on verso of unused notices re. 75th birthday (1959) (Box 56, Folder 1735)
      - Reviews: clippings, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1735a)
    - "Tryptichon der russischen Volkseele": typescript, carbon, initialled (Box 56, Folder 1736)
    - "Tschehow - Chekhov": for radio, typescript, corrected with holograph additions; and typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 56, Folder 1737)
    - "Tverdaia pozitsiia": clipping from Armiia i Flot Svobodnoi Rossii #159, photostat, 1917 Jul 11 (Box 56, Folder 1738)
    - "Typen der russischen Volksfrömmigkeit": typescript, corrected, signed (Box 56, Folder 1739)
    - "Über den Geist unserer Zeit": lecture, typescript carbon (2 c.), corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1740)
    - "Die unvergessene Stunde": typescript, carbon (Box 57, Folder 1741)
    - "Verfall und Aufbau der Persönlichkeit": lecture, typescript, corrected, and typescript, carbon, with holograph notes (Box 57, Folder 1742)
    - "Verfall und Aufbau der Persönlichkeit": for radio, typescript, corrected, signed (Box 57, Folder 1743)
    - "Verpflichtende Realitäten. Zu Josef Mackiewicz' Roman 'Der Weg ins Nirgendwo'": page proof, corrected (Box 57, Folder 1744)
    - "Die Verpflichtung zur Persönlichkeit": lecture, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1745)
    - "Voina i revoliutsiia": typescript and two carbons of five articles [published in Armiia i Flot Svobodnoi Rossii ] (Box 57, Folder 1746)
    - "Voina i revoliutsiia": clipping, photostat, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1747)
    - "Vom Geist unserer Zeit": lecture, holograph and typescript, 1959 Feb 6 (Box 57, Folder 1748)
    - "Vorwort zu Gagarin": typescript, carbon, corrected, in re E. A. Gagarin, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1749)
    - "Der Wahrheitsbegriff der Gesellschaftslehre": lecture, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1750)
    - "Walt Whitman & Leo Tolstoi": lecture, holograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1751)
    - "Was verliert Europa, wenn es Russland verliert?": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 57, Folder 1752)
    - "Das Wechselspiel zwischen Opferbereitschaft und Freiheit": lecture, holograph (Box 57, Folder 1753)
    - "Weit mehr als ein Bild": clipping from Die Welt, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1754)
    - "Das Weltschau Dostojewskiis": holograph, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1755)
    - "Wer ist Alexander Feodorowitsch Kerenski"
      - Typescript, carbon, corrected, of Russian text, entitled "Kto takoi Aleksandr Fedorovich Kerenskii? Demokrat i ob"edinenie russkoi emigratsii" (Box 57, Folder 1756)
      - Clipping from Die neue Zeitung, 1951 Aug 25/26 (Box 57, Folder 1757)
    - "Ein Werk aus europäischer Überlieferung. (Eine Festrede fur Prof. Karl Muth)": typescript, corrected, signed. On the second anniversary of Muth's death (Box 57, Folder 1758)
    - "Das Wesen der Ikone": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 57, Folder 1759)
    - "Das Wesen der Kunst": speech, holograph with pasted page proofs. Notation: "PEN Club" (Box 57, Folder 1760)
    - "Das Wesen der russische Kultur": typescript, carbon, corrected; and holograph. Radio speech (Box 57, Folder 1761)
    - "Das Wesen des Films": typescript, carbon, corrected (Box 57, Folder 1762)
    - "Wesenzüge des russischen Geistes": review of lecture, and reviews of other lectures in series held by Schweizerisches Institut für Auslandforshung", 1956 (Box 57, Folder 1763)
    - "Das Wunschbild Europa": holograph (Box 57, Folder 1764)
    - "Wird Europa sein Ostersonntag Feiern?": typescript, corrected and carbon (Box 57, Folder 1765)
    - "Wjatscheslaw Iwanow": typescript, carbon, corrected, fragment, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1766)
    - "Wladimir Solowjew": for radio, typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1767)
    - "Wladimir Solowjew": clipping (3 c.) from Der Rheinische Merkur No. 11, 1957 Nov 15 (Box 57, Folder 1768)
    - "Ein Wort ans Theaterpublikum": typescript, carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1769)